You know what I would love to do?
I would love to... fix that flat for you.
but I can't. I mean...
It's your only tux.
and you're late for your wedding.
How could I be late?
We've just met.
I'm a lot friendlier than he is.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Wow!
Kick in the butt. ain't it?
I never felt anything like it.
Ooh. who makes this?
Oh. this?
This is an experimental model.
Look at that.
- Oh. that's. uh. sheet lightning.
- I never saw lightning like that before.
And there are no clouds.
I can see the stars.
You know. that's about where they
set off the first atomic bomb.
No kidding.
And some people say there's
still a top secret project out there.
Something to do with
the deep space probe or a...
- Control!
- What's happening. Gooshie?
He's leaping.
Ziggy said no. but Sam's leaping.
- He can't leap. We're not ready.
- Tell Sam that!
- Put him on!
- I can't. He's in the accelerator.
Al-Al. what do I do?
Nothing. Any interference
could kill him.
I'll be there in two minutes.
Hang on. beautiful.
We did it.
Did what?
I can't remember.
I can't remember anything.
Who am I?
Where am I?
I'll put the coffee on. Tom.
Oh. boy.
I'm in big trouble here.
I don't even remember going to bed
with this woman. whoever she is.
And whoever she is.
she's certainly... pregnant.
Very pregnant.
Good morning.
What will I be you okay?
The secretary of state
appeared to be acting as a go-between...
at the United Nations in an effort to cool
down the heightened tensions between...
Tom. better hurry up.
Bird Dog's gonna be here to pick you up
in about 10 minutes.
Oh. honey. the P.X. was out
of your shaving cream.
so I got you some of that stuff. uh...
What do you call it? The one with
the cute little signs on the highway.
"Burma Shave?"
Oh. that's it.
Burma Shave.
I love those little signs.
What's taking you so long?
You gotta hurry up. Come on.
Get in there.
Oh. Tom. Sometimes...
It's a dream.
That's it. I'm dreaming.
All I have to do is flow with it.
and I'll wake up.
Shave.
The sooner you shave.
the sooner you'll wake up.
Oh. God.
It smells real.
It feels real.
What the hell is happening?
Tom?
Honey. what's wrong? Who
do you see in the mirror?
Oh. Tom. would you cut it out?
You nearly scared me into delivering.
Who do you see in the mirror?
You.
- Me?
- And me.
Oh.
Oh. I look awful.
Most women bloom
when they get pregnant. I shrivel.
Tom. I look like a prune.
My name's not Tom.
Honey. you're supposed to say.
"Peg. I love prunes."
- What do you mean your name's not Tom?
- Daddy. Captain Birdell's on the phone.
- I'm a daddy.
- Tom. are you sick?
Oh. honey. you're not gonna fly
if you're sick. are you?
Fly?
Mikey. tell Captain Birdell that Daddy will
call him as soon as he gets out of the shower.
Roger. And get his number. You know
him. He never sleeps at the B.O.Q
555-2231.
Daddy's in the shower.
What's your number?
5-5-5
Tom. what are you up to?
I'm calling my office.
- But that's Block field 8-4-7.
- What the hell's wrong with the phone?
You're dialing too many numbers.
Too many? Maybe not enough.
What's the area code?
Area code? You never tell us
codes. Dad. That's secret stuff.
Secret? What the hell
is secret about an area code?
If you're testing one of your gags on us. I
don't have time for it and neither do you.
That's the morning report on KHOl.
Stay tuned for all the denizens
of Doodyville...
with Buffalo Bob and Howdy Doody.
Well. Howdy Doody. kids.
- And howdy. Buffalo Bob.
- Howdy there. Mr. Doody.
Boys and girls at home and all
our kids here in the gallery. let's go!
It's Howdy Doody time
Bob Smith and Howdy too
Wave howdy-do to you
Okay.
It's not a dream.
It's a nightmare.
And if it's a nightmare.
sooner or later.
there's gonna be a bogeyman.
Until the bogeyman showed up.
I decided to ride out the dream.
Not that I had a choice.
Everyone seemed to think it was 1956.
and that I was an air force
captain named Tom Stratton...
with a wife called Peg
and one and two-thirds children.
Evidently. my best friend
was the officer behind the wheel.
a Captain Birdell. who
everyone simply called Bird Dog.
It didn't take long to find out why.
Hey. Hey-hey-hey. hoo-hoo.
Look at this.
Oh. my.
And I don't see a wedding ring.
Good morning. sweet pea.
How are you?
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Captain Bill Birdell and...
well. my facially wounded friend
here is Captain Tom Stratton.
You might've heard of us.
We're the only two pilots...
in the entire United States Air Force
brave enough to fly the X-2.
Oh?
What about Tony LaMott?
Oh. Lord.
Don't tell me you've been led astray
by that junior birdman.
Captain LaMott might have
a complicated wristwatch.
but he ain't anywhere close
to being otherwise test pilot equipped.
This being Friday.
I assume you're...
staying at the ranch
as his weekend guest?
Well. I'm staying at the ranch.
Then I'll anticipate a dance tonight.
And the sonic booms you hear today
will be dedicated to you.
"Only two guys brave
enough to fly the X-2."
You gotta impress the ladies.
pard. if you wanna score.
Besides that. it's true.
What if I told you I couldn't fly?
You sick?
No. I just...
When I woke up this morning.
couldn't remember how to fly.
I like it.
It's so crazy. I like it.
Who you gonna pull it on?
It's not a joke.
You sound like you mean it.
I do.
Damn. Tom. that's what makes you
the best. that sincere look.
Hell. if I could lie with a straight face
like you. my bird-dogging rate would double.
Hey. what say
we pull it on Weird Ernie.
Weird Ernie? Yeah. we'll tell him
that flying faster than Mach 2...
is affecting our minds.
Affecting your minds how?
It seems the faster I fly.
the less I remember about it.
I've experienced that. And I'm starting
to forget things. like my wife's birthday.
I never forgot Lucy's birthday
until I flew at Mach 2.5.
Last time I busted Mach 2.
I forgot where I parked my car.
That's fascinating.
Dr. Berger. could you design a test to
quantify these apparent memory losses?
- I should be able to come up with something.
- Good. Good.
This is a most interesting development.
Thank you. gentlemen.
Before we mount up. there's one more thing.
We believe the fire warning light...
Captain Birdell encountered at Mach 2.6
was a result of inadequate insulation.
We've rewired the system.
and we expect no further problems.
What's all this "we" stuff?
You gonna be up there with me?
I wish I could. Captain LaMott.
I truly wish I could.
But as you know. my war wounds
physically disqualify me.
If you should experience
a red light around Mach 2.6.
shut down until the chase plane
can catch up and check you over...
for visible signs of fire.
A fella could
be barbecued doing that.
You get a fire warning light. Tony.
I recommend you punch out.
- You didn't eject.
- Yeah. but I'm a damn hero.
You know. I like that guy.
He kind of reminds me of me
back in the old days.
All right. all right. If there are no further
questions. gentlemen. let's mount up.
Well. he swallowed that
hook. line and slide rule.
Now. ain't this a kick in the butt?
Chase One. hold on niner east.
Mother Hen. you are cleared to roll.
The pattern is yours.
Good luck.
You're my best friends.
I need your honest opinion here.
Uh-oh. Which thigh
has less stretch marks?
Oh. Lord.
My right one. Okay?
Or my left?
Gosh. Peg.
You know. I think this
one has less. My right?
They're not as wide either.
Really?
This is the one I'm using
my cactus cream on.
No!
Yes!
I gotta stop drinking so much coffee.
It's making me jumpy.
Yeah.
Given enough time.
you can get used to anything.
even a nightmare.
All you have to do is relax and...
trust those around you.
When did you get
into the import business?
What are you talking about?
That long-legged honey...
staying at the ranch
this weekend.
What's he do. Tom.
smell 'em out?
It's a natural gift. son.
It's a natural gift.
Sort of like
a bird dog flushing quail.
Yeah. yeah.
Well. I gotta mount up.
You know. I'm actually
beginning to enjoy this.
I mean. here I am. a daring air force
test pilot who doesn't have to fly.
Well. she's all yours. pard.
Take her up to 25 while
I answer Mother Nature.
Mother Hen heading 2-5-0-2-6-0...
at 12.000 and dropping.
Mother Hen. Edwards. Radar indicates you are
in a 40-degree-per-minute turn to the right.
Are you experiencing a problem?
Over.
Whoa-ooo-ooo!
- What's wrong?
- I can't fly.
Bird Dog. Tom.
can you read me? Over.
Mother Hen. Edwards.
Do you have a problem? Over.
Uh. Edwards. this is Mother Hen.
We must've had a bubble
in the hydraulic system.
'cause for a while. this bird
was flying like a Mack truck.
Whatever it was.
we must have burped it out.
We are continuing our climb
up to 25.000.
You save it for Weird Ernie. pard.
You ain't never gonna sucker me.
Just don't ask me to fly.
Edwards. Mother Hen.
Level at 25.000.
Roger. Mother Hen.
You are clear to drop.
Good luck.
Hey. Tony. I'm tired of
hauling your butt around.
I'm gonna cut you loose and see which
of us gets back to that blonde first.
Is everybody back there
okay where they're at?
Yeah. looks fine to me.
All right. 240 indicated.
Here we go. ladies.
Drop in ten. nine. eight.
seven. six.
five. four.
three. two.
one.
Bombs away.
Ride her. cowboy.
Mach 1.3 and accelerating.
Nosing over.
One-nine. Mach 2.
All right.
She's leveling off.
65.000.
Sixty-six.
Level at 71.000.
Mach 2.4.
On profile.
All right. Starting my run.
Firing rocket three.
Mach 2.5.
Two-six.
Outside skin temperature. 683.
Ain't no fire warning light.
I guess we beat that gremlin.
Mach 2.7.
Two-eight.
Skin temperature. 800.
Fire warning light.
Rockets off.
Everything looks okay.
Mach 2.4.
2.3.
Nah. I think it's
another false alarm.
- Hey. where are you. Dougie?
- Five miles behind you at 30.000.
Roger. Coming back to you
for a look-see.
Don't turn above Mach 2.
Oh. I lost her!
Did you see it?
There.
Oh. God.
Well. the X-2 didn't get him.
but she's sure gonna auger him in.
- You think so?
- Yeah. he's got that. uh. that sick calf look.
Here we go. gang.
Bird Dog's about to pounce.
Shoot. he's the only pilot left
in the B.O.Q
Be awful lonesome in there
without him.
How would you know?
You never sleep in the B.O.Q
As nightmares go. this one is definitely
taking a turn for the better.
Even at six months. I found Peg...
stunningly beautiful.
Although. I doubt she'd believe it.
It could be that pregnant women hold
some strange attraction for me. but...
I think it's Peg.
Whatever it is. the chemistry
is definitely working and.
well. I'll just have to
keep telling myself...
I'm not really her husband. Tom.
Would you like to dance?
What?
Dance.
With this stomach?
I can reach around it.
Well. I wanna know who you've
been dancing with. mister.
What? Tom. you may be the
best pilot in the air force.
but you were born
with two left feet... until tonight.
Maybe I just needed
a well-rounded partner.
Peg?
Hmm?
Who's that guy by the jukebox?
That's Doug.
No. no. no.
The guy in the tux.
A tux? In here?
You don't see a man in a black tux
standing by the jukebox?
Tom. Tom.
Everything is so nice.
Let's not spoil it.
Either someone blocked Peg's view
of the guy in the tux.
or the bogeyman had arrived.
Whichever it was.
I was going to find out.
Oh. Tom. No. you're
six months along. Peg.
At six months. you dance one.
and then sit one out.
Doctor's orders.
But I feel fine.
and we never get
a chance to dance.
This is my favorite song.
I don't want you to overdo it.
Look. we've got all night. okay?
Okay.
I'm gonna go feed the old
jukebox. I'll be right back.
Isn't this great?
I mean. isn't this just great?
Brings back so many old memories.
Hey. have they got
"Be-Bop-A-Lula" on there?
Got me through some long.
cold nights at M.I.T.
"Be-Bop" and a little
Lithuanian girl named Danesa.
She was in the chemistry lab
researching the...
Am I dead?
What?
Dead. Am I dead?
It would explain a lot.
I could be in a reverse reincarnation
that's entered in midlife.
That's a good one. Sam.
You know my name.
I'm not that wasted.
Why do you know who I am
when no one else does?
Are you serious? Dead
serious. No pun intended.
Oh. my God.
You really don't
recognize me. do you? No.
Or remember the experiment.
What experiment?
What do you remember
prior to waking up this morning?
Other than my name and a telephone
number. not a lot. What experiment?
If I'm part of an experiment. then this
all isn't a psychotic hallucination. is it?
Is it?
Oh. God.
that putz Ziggy was right.
Ziggy? I remember a Ziggy.
A little guy with bad breath.
You're slipping; pard.
Nobody's gonna fall for that old
"talking to somebody who ain't there" gag.
Oh. God. What the hell?
What are we gonna do?
- We're in a rotten fix.
I told him not to...
Though I don't know
Many words of praise
Please. God.
I'd like to wake up now.
Put on your bonnet
your cape and your glove
And come with me
This is KCV530. Victorville.
Here's Velton Bunch
and the Dovetones.
I never realized how hard it was
to follow a road without striping.
Striping?
I was just thinking that.
you know.
if they would paint white stripes
along the side of the road.
it would be easier to see.
That's a very good idea. Tom.
I got a few of them.
Tonight was fun.
Good.
It was a little scary too.
Why scary?
Oh. I don't know.
Maybe because...
you wanted to dance.
It's not the first time
we danced.
And you didn't drink more
than one or two beers...
or talk flying.
I can't remember
the last time you sat...
at a table full of pilots
and you didn't talk airplanes.
It seemed to me that's
all we talked about.
That's all they talked about.
You didn't say a word.
I wasn't in a talkative mood.
You were at the jukebox.
"Why is it..."
"When you..."
"Try to pass..."
"The guy in front..."
- "Goes twice as fast?"
- "Burma Shave."
Oh. it feels nice.
How did it work?
Better than my electric razor.
uh. would.
I don't use an electric razor. do I? No.
No. Tom.
What's going on?
I wish I knew.
- Honey. just tell me. okay?
- What if I told you my name wasn't Tom?
You said that this morning
in the bathroom. It's Sam.
Don't ask me what my last name is
because I can't remember it.
I look in a mirror. and I see...
Tom Stratton. I guess.
but he's not me.
I can't fly.
In fact.
I don't know what I can do.
When I woke up this morning.
I didn't know you or Mikey...
or anyone else at the base.
I know it sounds like I belong
in a loony bin. but it's the truth.
The reason I'm acting different
is because I am different.
- I'm not your Tom.
- Oh. Tom.
Oh. look.
Please don't...
Then stop doing this. okay?
You asked me to explain...
Just stop it. Tom.
I'm sorry. Peg.
I'm being a real nerd.
You were right.
I'm setting up a gag.
- Thank God.
- I shouldn't have tried it on you.
Oh. honey. you had me
scared to death.
I thought you had a brain tumor
or something.
I never thought of that.
What?
Bird Dog and I have been dreaming up
theories to explain why I can't fly.
You see. that's the joke.
I tell Weird Ernie
that I forgot how to fly.
You tell Weird Ernie that
you forgot how to fly. Yeah.
Tom. that is the stupidest thing
I've ever heard.
I don't know.
It sounds pretty plausible to me.
Tom?
Hmm?
What's a nerd?
Well. it. uh...
What's the matter?
What? Nothing. Go back to sleep.
Okay.
That's all I need.
a good night's sleep.
I'll figure it out in the morning
when I milk the cows.
"Milk the cows"?
I was raised
on a dairy farm in Indiana...
until I was 18.
I went to college at...
Damn. I can't remember.
Stick to the farm.
I was raised on a farm with...
my sister Kate.
Katie married a naval officer.
Um. Lieutenant John...
No. Jim.
Jim Bonick.
Yeah. Katie and Jim Bonick.
Mom's lived with them in Hawaii
ever since...
Dad died in '74.
But this is '56.
My dad is still alive.
Operator.
I'd like long distance. please.
Long Distance.
Indiana. please.
Elk Ridge. Indiana.
Number. please.
I'm-I'm-I'm trying. Operator.
but it's been a long time.
Um. it's...
Oakdell.
Yeah. that's it.
Uh. Oakdell...
Sir. why don't you give me
the name of the party.
and I will ring
Elk Ridge Information.
Sir?
Sir. do you want
Elk Ridge Information?
Dad? What's wrong?
I'm just...
I'm catching a cold.
Wanna skip the fishing trip?
- What?
- It's Saturday.
You said we'd go fishing today.
But we don't have to
if you don't feel good.
What are you talking about?
Nothing cures a cold
faster than a fishing trip.
You don't wanna do that.
I just did that to show you
what not to do.
I'll bring it back now. and I'll
show you how it should be done.
Now. remember. Mikey.
even your best fly fisherman...
gets his fly snagged now and then.
But it's the old pro
who can bring it back without...
Can I try now. Dad?
You stay here and fish this.
uh. pool. all right?
I'm gonna fish further upstream. Roger.
Dad. I know you're trying
to make me look good.
Yeah.
Is that a Ginger Quill
spent wing?
Or maybe a Blue Dunn?
I don't know.
I got such a damn hangover.
It could be a Coors pop-top.
Don't yell. please!
I should've stayed in bed
with Tina.
You still don't
remember me. huh?
That's sad. pal. very sad.
My name is Albert.
Albert what. I can't tell you.
because it's restricted.
Most of what you're gonna
wanna know is restricted.
So it'll be easier for us if you
don't ask a lot of questions.
- What are you?
- That's a question. Sam.
I'm a man. like you.
Mmm.
- Not like me.
- Oh. no. uh. this isn't me.
This is. uh.
a neurological hologram.
It's an image that only
you can see and hear.
Created by a subatomic
agitation of carbon quarks...
tuned to the mesons
of my optic and optic neurons?
- You got it.
- How did I know that?
Ziggy has come up with five
different scenarios to ex...
Ziggy!
Ziggy. a little guy with bad breath.
No. that's Gooshie.
He programs Ziggy.
Ziggy's a hybrid computer.
Hybrid computers and neurological
holograms didn't exist in 1956.
Only in theory.
But this is '56.
Well. it is for you.
It is not for me.
What's my last name?
If you can't remember. I
can't tell you. It's important.
But it's also on top of Ziggy's
no-no list. double-starred.
Why?
I can't tell you that either.
What the hell can you tell me?
Basically. what you already know.
That you're. uh. part of
a time-travel experiment...
that went a little caca.
"A little caca"?
- How little caca?
- Well. you're here. which is a biggie.
I mean. that's a first.
It's Nobel Prize time.
You should be proud of that.
And?
And. uh. uh.
we're experiencing...
technical difficulties in.
uh. retrieving you.
That's great. Al.
I wake up in '56 with a memory
like Swiss cheese.
and you're experiencing
technical difficulties?
Whose brainchild is this. yours?
No. not mine.
I haven't got a lot of time. I have
to find out which of these scenarios...
can explain why we couldn't
retrieve you this morning.
You tried? Of course we
tried. You wouldn't leap.
So now it's my fault.
Possibly.
Did you tell anyone
that you're not Tom Stratton?
Sort of.
Oh. Sam.
Retrieving you is dependent upon
everyone here...
believing that you're
the person you replaced.
They didn't believe me. I look in
a mirror. and I don't believe me.
That's to be expected.
To us. Tom looks just like you.
He's with you?
Of course.
How do you think we located you?
When you went in. he came out.
If it's any consolation.
his memory is full of holes too.
Now. everyone has to believe
that you're Tom Stratton...
if we're gonna be able
to retrieve you on Tuesday.
Tuesday.
Tuesday's gonna be a little late.
I'm. uh...
I'm scheduled to test-fly
the X-2 on Monday.
Did you ever think
of taking flying lessons?
Just a thought.
All right. give me the big one.
Right down the middle.
Not bad. not bad. Right in
the glove. Right in the glove.
Right down the middle. No batter.
no batter. no batter. no batter.
What you need
is a little Texas sauce.
Yeah! Ow. Mmm.
How does he do it?
Probably wearing his hat.
Sometimes Doug
wears his goggles.
Well. I think it's sexy.
I mean. if anything.
that spin became even flatter.
Hi. baby.
I mean. I didn't want to punch out inverted.
but what the hell else could I do?
All right.
Yeah!
Wow!
Did you see that roll and flip
he did at the top. Dad?
What do you call it?
You got me.
- The chandelle. Mikey.
- Wow! It sure was something.
Yeah. it sure was.
I'd better help your mom.
Aw. Dad.
Unless you wanna set the table.
Hey. Captain Crawford.
wanna play catch?
Sure do.
Fire one on in there. Mikey.
Hi.
You okay?
I'm fine.
You look a little pale.
Yeah. well. it's the heat.
I'll never get used to it.
You want me to help?
I make a mean Caesar salad.
I'm just kidding.
I know.
But not about how you look.
Well. that's your fault.
That's not what I meant.
Look. I'm fine.
I really am.
Why don't you just go back
on out there with Mikey?
You know. you haven't spent this much
time with him since he was hit by the bus.
Okay.
Hey. flyboy.
Come and get it.
Uh...
Got to eat trout
while it's sizzling.
Yeah.
Why don't you take the salad out?
I'll get the rolls.
Yeah.
I'm sorry to pull you
from your barbecue.
but Dr. Berger and I have just
finished a questionnaire...
to test Captain Birdell's theory that Mach 3
flight has a negative effect on the memory.
Quite frankly. if this theory had
come from you. I'd be skeptical.
We all know your penchant
for practical jokes. eh?
Doctor. any memory loss
I suffer won't be faked.
We're going to call it the
Ernst-Berger Engramic Standard.
200 questions designed to
benchmark a person's memory.
I thought we were gonna call it
the Berger-Ernst Engramic Standard.
Hi. Tom.
Hi.
These questions should give us
a cross section of your memory.
Some. like your age. place of birth.
are the usual statistics.
But I think you'll find
most are rather unusual.
What was the coldest
you've ever been?
Who was your second-best friend
in college?
Where did you first make love?
Well. at least you didn't ask to who.
Dr. Ernst suggested that.
but where is as meaningful
and more discreet.
Sort of a personal "Trivial Pursuit"?
Not a bad name.
The Berger-Ernst
Engramic Trivial Pursuit.
Ernst-Berger. We'll need this filled
out before you take off on Monday.
You'll fill it out
again when you land.
If there are any significant changes in your
memory. we should be able to detect them.
- Any questions. Captain?
- Uh. no. no.
It seems simple enough. I'll. hum...
I'll have it for you on Monday.
Doctors.
Doctor. we could be on the verge
of a momentous discovery.
Or the butt of a momentous joke.
Pretty simple. huh?
Can't you just
fade in or something?
You tell me how to fade in agitated carbon
quarks. and I'll make the Scientific Journal.
Just don't sneak up on me. You
still don't remember our project?
Bad enough I have to give Dick-and-Jane
explanations to the president.
I've gotta give you one too.
All right.
One end of this string
represents your birth.
The other end. your death. You tie the
ends together. and your life is a loop.
Ball the loop...
and the days of your life
touch each other out of sequence.
Therefore. leaping from one point
of the string to another...
Would move you backward or forward
within your own lifetime.
Which is our project.
Quantum Leap!
I can't remember.
Al! I wish you would stop doing that.
What?
Walking through things.
Well. you want me to walk around something that
isn't even here? All right. I'll walk around it.
There. How's that?
Why-Why isn't it here?
I'm a hologram to you. right? Well. you and
everything around you is a hologram to me.
You're in the imaging
chamber. You remember.
Vaguely. A cavern somewhere. New Mexico.
What year is it there?
You'll find that out...
if we get you back. If?
Well. see. Ziggy's theory is really...
It's a load of crap.
I mean. you gotta believe
that God or time or something...
was just waiting for
your quantum leap to. uh.
to correct a mistake.
A mistake in time?
Something that happened in the life
of Captain Tom Stratton in '56.
since he's the one you bounced out.
Once that's put right.
you'll snap back like a pimp's suspenders.
Once what's put right?
Tom Stratton was killed
trying to break Mach 3 in the X-2.
If Ziggy's right.
all you have to do is break Mach 3...
and live.
Hey!
No way.
Hey. pal. it's not my theory.
There's gotta be another way.
The next one's only got
a 52% chance of working.
I'll take it.
It requires you to be at ground zero
during an atomic detonation.
You asked.
What else have you got?
This isn't a shopping list. you know.
The odds drop into
the low teens after that.
Your best shot is freezing the brain
until all electrical activity has ceased.
That's called death.
I never said it would be easy.
Hey. slow down. will ya?
I'm fighting a hangover.
All right. you want a sure thing?
I got it for you.
You don't do anything. You just live.
Barring accidental death...
or a fatal disease.
you'll be back in 40 years.
That's your safest option.
And Tom Stratton?
He'll go on living forward
from where he's at now.
Technically. he could end up
the oldest man alive.
Well. what about Peg and Mikey? I don't want to
hurt them. but I can't go on pretending I'm Tom.
Hey. they were gonna
lose him on Monday anyway.
Of course.
if you bust Mach 3 and survive.
they could have him around for
another 30 or 40 years. I can't fly!
I'll be your copilot.
You're a hologram.
I'm also an ex-astronaut. The hardest part
about flying is taking off and landing.
The B-50 does the first part for you. After
that. you just fire a couple of rockets.
hang on to the stick
and ka-za-zoom. Mach 3.
And the second part?
Landing?
You could never land the X-2. not
even with my help. So. you don't.
I eject?
Mmm.
X-2 does a crash and burn. You float
back to earth on a pillow of silk.
The moment you touch down. you leap forward.
Tom leaps back. and the broad and I...
are gone to Las Vegas.
It might work.
Of course it'll work.
A minute ago
you said it was crap.
That was before I thought it out.
Tom?
You should be asleep.
And you shouldn't be?
You're worried about breaking
the record tomorrow. aren't you?
No.
Oh. honey. you'll do it.
You're gonna be the fastest man alive.
Tom...
promise me.
What?
No. you have to promise first.
Well. that's silly. How can I promise
something if I don't know what...
Just promise.
I promise.
Now. what did I promise?
I'll tell you tomorrow night.
Thanks. guys.
Well. ready to become
the fastest man on earth?
Ready as I'll ever be.
Oh. What did you
think of this. Tom?
Well. I'm not sure how useful it'll be
to gauge a memory loss. but. uh.
filling it out last night sure brought back
a lot of old ones for me.
Well. my boobs
are as big as Marilyn's.
Lucy. you're
five months pregnant.
Well. maybe she is too. Why else
would a guy like Miller marry her?
Guess.
Sally. he's a writer. They're only
used to the finer things in life.
Honey. there is nothing finer in life.
You are so bad!
There's a yellow rose in Texas
That I am gonna see
Nobody else could miss her
Not half as much as me
She cried so when I left her
Hey. wait a minute. Listen to this.
It like to broke my heart
And if I ever find her
we'll never fall apart
If you don't clear this radio.
Captain Birdell.
the only yellow rose you'll be seeing will
be the one I'll shove up your afterburners.
- Is that clear? Over.
- Uh. that's a roger. Edwards.
Read this.
"Date of birth.
August 8th. 19... 53."
- Well. that's a typo. He means 1923.
- Keep reading.
"What had the most positive impact on
me in high school? Answer: miniskirts.
"What had the most negative impact
on me in high school? Answer: panty hose?"
It's time to mount up. Tom.
Hey. Tom. this is gonna sound
a little weird. but...
right before I got the fire warning light.
I swear I smelled coffee brewing.
Maybe it's one of
Weird Ernie's gremlins.
Yeah. maybe.
Good luck. Tom.
Where are you. Albert?
Hmm.
"When feeling lonely. I rent a video
and microwave some popcorn."
This is gibberish.
Very creative gibberish.
Captain Stratton has answered
each question as if he had...
been born in '53
and lived in the future.
Then this whole memory loss thing
is another one of their hoaxes.
I'm afraid so.
Well. how stupid do they think I am?
Pet rocks. Water beds.
What was it he said he was expelled
from college for? Uh. streaking.
He's got a sick mind. Doctor.
They all do.
Maybe they have to.
Okay.
Uh. Albert?
Locked tight. All set. Captain.
Good luck.
Edwards. Mother Hen.
Level at 25.000.
Roger. Mother Hen.
You are clear to drop.
Good luck.
Ten. nine. eight.
seven. six. five.
four. three. two.
one.
Albert!
Bombs away.
Albert.!
X-2. Chase One.
Do you have a problem? Over.
I can't fly.
Relax. I can.
Al?
Al? Where are you?
Right here.
Hey. Tom. do you read me?
Come in. X-2.
Follow my lead.
Light off one and two.
It's a kick in the butt. ain't it?
Match my movements.
Where the hell were you?
I was at the Laker game.
It went into overtime.
A ball game? I nearly died
because you were at a ball game?
It wasn't just a ball game.
It was a play-off game.
At the party later.
I met this dish named Martha.
I guess I can thank God you didn't
spend the night with this Martha.
Well. I did.
Uh. coming up on Mach 1.
Coming up on Mach 1.
Mach 1.3.
Nosing over.
Mach 1.3. 50.000.
N-N-Nosing over.
Now ease the stick forward.
That's enough.
Mach 1.7.
Mach 2. 68. 69.
Mach 2.
Level at 70.000.
Mach 2.4. On a profile.
Mach 2.4.
On profile.
Wow.!
It's incredible!
- What now?
- Punch three and go for it.
Mach 2.4. 2.5.
Outside skin temperature. 685.
- Mach 2.7. Skin temperature. 750.
- Ride her. cowboy.
Mach 2.8.
- Do you hear that?
- Mach 2.9. Yes.
Tony didn't smell coffee.
He heard it perking.
It's the fuel. Sam.
The heat is boiling the fuel.
Shut 'em down. Sam. Shut 'em down!
Shut 'em down.!
Pull. Sam. Eject.!
I'm still here.
No. damn it. I'm still here.!
Al!
You know. Captain. we could be combing the
desert with tweezers and little glass jars...
looking for what's left of you.
You guys are all alike. Losing your
plane's worse than losing your wife.
I'd trade my ex-wife
for any wreck they got.
I'm still here.
Hmm. 'Bout time you realized it.
What now? I'm going to
take your blood pressure.
We could try the A-bomb
theory. No. thank you.
Well. I'm sorry. but it's
necessary. It's not my theory. Sam.
I never bought into that "good deed.
put time right" bull. Not really.
So I'm stuck here?
I don't think so.
Maybe not. A few tests at the hospital.
and you should be able to go home.
Maybe you could leap back when you least
suspect it. like tonight when you're sleeping.
Do you really believe that?
Absolutely. I don't know.
I don't see any reason to keep you
in the hospital. But in the meantime.
there's no reason for me to stay here.
and I would feel really bad...
if Martha woke up and found out that I'd gone
without even saying good morning. you know?
It's not nice.
Unless your blood pressure
keeps elevating.
Dr. Berger.
please contact the ward nurse.
Daddy!
Hey.
Hey. I'm okay.
Peg went into premature labor
when she heard the crash.
Okay. I'll be right.
Look. I know you want
to be with your mom.
And you will.
But. uh.
right now I want you to stay
with Sally and Lucy. okay?
They're both pregnant. and they're
very frightened. You understand?
Yes. sir.
She'll be fine. son.
I promise.
Tom. what...
Is she dilated any further?
Tom. Tom!
Oh.! Oh.!
Oh!
Oh. I knew
you'd keep your promise.
It'll take more than
a gremlin to kill me.
Hey. did you set a record?
I guess so.
Oh. I'm so proud of you!
Look at me. Look at me.
Take a deep breath.
Hold it...
and let it out like this.
Okay?
Where did you learn to do that? Premed.
Oh. Tom!
Excuse me. Tom?
I'll be right back.
Tom. this is Dr. Blaustein.
It's not good. Captain. The baby's
gonna arrive at least nine weeks premature.
The nearest neonatal
intensive care unit's in L.A.
Now. we've got a plane standing by...
but considering the shock
that your wife's been through...
I don't want to risk moving her.
It's your decision. Tom. I'd recommend
delivering here and flying the baby to L.A.
The baby won't have a chance.
Not much. but your wife will.
Dr. Cooper to O.R. 3.
How far apart are
the contractions?
It's early labor. It's just
started. How far dilated?
Two centimeters.
and the cervix is partial effaced.
Then it's early enough to stop. Captain.
once labor's started you can't stop it.
Of course you can. Start her on
a beta sympathomimetic. A what?
A beta sympathomimetic.
I'm not sure which one. Obstetrics isn't my
specialty. Probably ritodrine or terbuta...
Hell. those didn't come out till the
late '70s. Excuse us a minute. Doctor.
Captain. the only reason I'm not
kicking you from here to the flight line...
is that woman down the hall needs you.
She doesn't have to deliver. I know what
I'm talking about. Now you're a doctor?
Evidently.
Tom. considering what
you've been through today.
I'm gonna make an allowance
for your behavior up to now.
But if you persist in wasting our time with
this little sham you and Captain Birdell...
are trying to perpetrate. mister.
I'll see you never fly again!
It's not a sham.
Those answers are true.
Dr. Ernst was right.
You are one sick bastard.
Alcohol.
A five percent solution of ethanol
alcohol in dextrose and water...
intravenously administered
will stop labor.
The technique was developed in the '60s. Beta
sympathomimetics replaced it in the '70s.
But it'll still work.
Use your brain. damn it!
What will an intravenous
five percent solution of alcohol do?
Get her instantly drunk.
which will interfere
with the oxytocins...
her brain's releasing
to stimulate the uterine contractions.
Thank you.
Did you hear any of that. Barry?
Yeah. I did.
What do you think? Well. let's give
it a try. Nurse. prepare an I.V...
Que sera. sera
Whatever will be. will be
The future's not ours to see
Que sera. sera
What will be. will be
Well. what do you think. boys?
We have Doris Day
for a patient. Well?
She's gonna have one beaut of a
hangover. but she's not gonna deliver.
Do you want to tell me how
in the hell Captain Stratton...
Barry. do me a favor.
Hmm?
Don't ask.
Hey. flyboy.
the squares are gone.
You wanna boogie?
I love you.
I love you too. Peg.
Hey. Fox.!
Fox. what ya posing for?
Ain't nobody gonna take your picture.
Nice catch. Foxy.
This is it. folks.
Down by five. the last of the ninth.
Unless the Bombers can pull a miracle and
win this final game of the 68th season.
it's the cellar
for the third year in a row.
The bottom of the ninth is brought to
you tonight. as it has been all year long.
by Shneck and Shneck
Funeral Parlors.
serving Waco and
the Texas Hill Country for 43 years.
All right. now. put some fire under it.!
Hustle. boys! Now hustle!
We're gonna beat these Okies.
Fox! Do something!
Me? Why me?
It's your dog.
He knew. The little sucker knew.
And he wasn't gonna stop barking
until they all knew.
Stray dogs are pretty common
on the farm belt.
and one of the first things my dad taught
me was how to face the wild ones down.
You look them straight in the eye.
and you let 'em know who's boss.
Of course. it had been a long time
since I was a kid.
Then again.
once you've got the touch.
you never lose it.
- That's the damnedest thing I ever saw.
- How'd you teach him that. Foxy?
Well... Aah!
Barnes lines a solid shot
down the aisle in right center.
Pace is chasing it back into the corner.
Barnes is rounding first.
Here comes the throw to second. and he
- Safe!
He's safe!
Well. the Bombers get their second hit
of the game. and it's a double! Oh!
No wonder they're in the cellar. They got
about as much enthusiasm as a $10 hooker.
Come on.
I want to watch the game.
Will you follow me?
- I can't. I'm up after Matt.
- Yeah. Right.
- Something wrong. Fox?
- Uh. no. I'm gonna...
I'll be back in a minute. I'm
just gonna... you know.
Make it snappy.
Strike!
The next son of a gun that swings at
the first pitch. I'm gonna fine 50 bucks!
Al!
How'd you get here so fast?
It's been a week since
you quantum leaped. A week?
A couple of minutes ago
I was in the hospital with Peg.
Well. you've been bouncing
around in time. Sam.
It may have seemed like
a couple of minutes to you.
but we've been popping
champagne for six days.
Oh. it was a hell of a party too.
Gooshie. he got so wasted that
he had Ziggy printing X-rated pictures.
And you know Brenda.
the cute little redhead in coding?
She got so turned on!
No. I don't know Brenda.
or I don't remember Brenda.
And I certainly don't care
how turned on she got.
I'm in a real identity crisis here. Al.
I mean. one minute I'm Tom Stratton.
and the next I'm a ball player named Fox.
Tim Fox. 32-year-old third baseman
for the Waco Bombers.
According to Ziggy. you hit... 415 in
'63 and got called up to Chicago...
where you broke your leg sliding into
second and got sent back down to recover.
That was five years ago.
Oh. boy!
Hey. come on. Sam.
We're missing the game!
The hell with the game!
It's your last one in organized ball.
In a couple of minutes
you're gonna fly out to center.
The Bombers are gonna finish
another season in the cellar.
and you're gonna hang up
your spikes. Then what?
Well. you're gonna open up a Kentucky
Fried Chicken franchise. What?
You'll marry a girl named Sue
and have two kids.
Of course. you don't have to be
around for all of that.
Soon as we can figure out what needs
to be put right. you'll leap outta here.
Like fly the X-2
to Mach 3 and live?
Hey. Ziggy blew it!
Yeah.
He didn't research it enough.
Originally. Tom Stratton not only died.
but his wife went into premature labor.
and the baby was stillborn.
And now?
Tom's alive!
Peg gave birth to a healthy baby girl.
seven pounds. eight ounces.
Funny thing.
They happened to name her Samantha.
Seems like someone wanted
both Tom and Samantha to survive.
Yeah.
Come on. Jackson's up.
He's gonna hit a homer with one on!
You're a vampire.
What? Neurological
holograms don't reflect. Sam.
Obviously when it comes to quantum
physics. you're still a mental slug.
But we can talk about this later.
Come on. I hate to miss the game.
You already know how
it's going to end.
I knew how it was gonna end
when I took Brenda into the filing room.
I still took her.
There's the homer.
Why didn't I leap all the way?
Twelve years in a blink isn't bad. pal. A
couple more of those. you'll be back home.
If I leap forward again.
What if I leap back?
That is always possible.
In other words. I could be
bouncing around in time forever?
No. Nobody lives forever.
What does Ziggy say I have to put right
to leap this time? He isn't saying.
What?
He's depressed.
He's a computer.
He's got a big ego.
I think he knows what you have to do. He's just
afraid to print it out in case he's wrong.
Who created this Ziggy?
You. Quantum Leap
is your project. Sam.
You're the genius behind it.
At least you were before
your brain got magna-foozled.
No. no. See. I'm a medical doctor.
I found that much out.
You hold six doctorates. Sam.
Medicine is just one of them.
Your special gift was quantum physics.
Time magazine even
called you the next Einstein.
The truth is...
if there's one guy who could
figure out how to bring you back...
it's you.
And I can't even
remember my name.
It's Beckett.
Sam Beckett.
Jackson hits a towering smash...
over the Shneck and Shneck billboard
in center field.!
And the Bombers have pulled
within a run. Ooo-wee.!
Long distance.
Long distance?
Yes. I'd like to call
a John Beckett...
in Elk Ridge. Indiana.
And I-I-I don't have the number.
John Beckett?
Yes. ma'am. Beckett.
One moment. please.
Hello?
Dad?
What? Who is this?
Hello? Hello?
Look. whoever this is.
I got no time for tomfoolery.
Please. don't hang up.
Who is this?
I- I'm a Beckett.
My father and your father
are related.
How?
Uh. they're brothers.
I'm John's son.
John's son? My God. he moved to
Australia when I was just a kid.
Huh! Listen to me telling you
what your father did.
That's all right.
What's your name?
Sam.
Well. I'll be darned.
I've named my boy Sam.
How about that?
You don't sound Australian. Sam.
Well. I-I-I travel a lot.
I don't believe it.!
Flash hit a stand-up double.
I don't want to disappoint
my dad. but I...
I don't think I'm gonna be able to
make it home for Thanksgiving this year.
Well. I know he'll understand.
I hope so.
It doesn't mean I don't love him.
I do. and I miss him a lot too.
even...
even if I never...
I never told him.
He knows.
You think so?
Well. a boy can't feel about his dad
the way you do without his knowing it.
Maybe.
But when I don't show for Thanksgiving.
it's-it's gonna hurt him.
Sam. it's nice to have
the children home for the holidays.
but sometimes it can't happen.
You're a young man trying to
make your mark in the world. and...
how you go about doing
that's a lot more important
to your father than
showing up for turkey.
At least it would be for me.
Coming from you. that means...
that means a lot.
Now you can't make it
to Australia for the holidays.
but... we're a lot closer.
Why don't you come up here?
We got plenty of room.
and Mom's pumpkin pie has taken a blue ribbon
at the Elk Ridge County Fair for ten years.
Well. I don't know
if I'll be able to. but I'm...
I'm sure gonna try.
Well. it doesn't have to be
Thanksgiving either.
You wanna drop by here
anytime. you're welcome.
I'll remember that.
Good-bye.
I love you. Dad.
Hey. Dad. that calf
is gonna drop any second.
I'll get my sweater. Sam.
I just talked to
my Uncle John's son from Australia.
He may come for the holidays.
Can he milk cows?
Come on.
Thank you.
You know. maybe this quantum leaping...
isn't such a bad deal after all.
Getting a second chance
to put things right.
to make the world a better place.
Who knows what I can accomplish
before I'm done.
Thanks. Al.
Go fly out.
I don't know. Al.
Maybe I'm here to win this one.
The tying run is on second. and the
potential winning run is coming up to bat!
Hey. Fox!
Tim. this is my last year too.
and. uh. I don't want
to end it in the cellar.
Go. Foxy! Go. Foxy!
Foxy! Foxy! Foxy!
Give me one with
a four-bagger in it. son.
Go on. Foxy.
Are you serious. Sam?
You notice who that kid kind of
looks like out there? Yeah.
Yeah? Yeah?
You're gonna fly to center.
Fox flied out to center.
I'm not Fox.
Yeah. well. you're not Roy Hobbs either.
Fox. representing the winning run.
steps to the plate.
A switch-hitter. Fox has 28 home runs
this year. 12 of them batting left-handed.
Be patient in there now!
Be patient!
Strike one!
Well. now. at least there's someone
around here who can follow orders.
Strike two!
That last one had to be
over 100 miles an hour.
I'll get the next one.
Did you ask for time?
No. Play ball.
All right. Let's go.
"When it comes to that
final out in life.
"whether you pop out.
ground out or fly out. remember.
Shneck and Shneck will always
be there to bring you home."
Fox steps back into the box.
He digs in.
Behind 0 and 2 in the count. he looks
determined not to let another pitch go by.
Strike three.!